A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.2, Series 100 International - Series 253 Washington FA387a
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.2, Series 100 International - Series 253 Washington
1910-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA387a
300.4 Cubic Feet
Other Finding Aids note
Other available finding aids describing Rockefeller Foundation records, Projects include:
FA386 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.1
FA388 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.3
Biographical/Historical note
The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.
Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.
The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.
As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.
As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.
Arrangement note
The project files are arranged in series according to country. Each state within the United States and every country or geographical area was assigned a three-digit number by RF staff. In addition, letters signifying program areas are used: for example, "A" indicates a grant in the Medical Sciences, and "C" Nursing. Material is organized within these letter/program subdivisions alphabetically by grant title. A grant title usually consists of a heading that includes the name of the institution or individual that received the grant. Thus each grant, or project, is filed individually in one or more folders.
File Plan note
RG 1.1, 1.2, and part of 1.3
Organization of the Rockefeller Foundation's archives:
RG 1 Projects
RG 2 General Correspondence
RG 3 Administration, Program and Policy
RG 4 China Medical Board
RG 5 International Health Board/Division
RG 6 Field Offices
RG 7 Treasurer's Office
RG 8 Comptroller
RG 9 Personnel
RG 10 Fellowships
RG 11 Information Services
RG 12 Diaries
RG 13 Oral Histories
RG 14 Counsel
RG 15 Secretary
RG 16 Minutes and Officers Actions
RG 17 Dockets
RG 18 Declinations (100F)
RG 19 Non-textual Materials
RG 20 Communications Office
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Confidential material in this record group has been segregated and is inaccessible. Each pertinent file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material within each file is not necessary.
Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: project files.
War relief; Tuberculosis; Viruses -- Research; Agriculture; Nursing; Diseases; Arts; Hookworm disease; Epidemiology; Philanthropy; Humanities; Hospitals; Scholarships; Social sciences -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Respiratory organs -- Diseases; Scarlatina -- Hospitals -- Administration; Public health administration; Public health -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Public health; Humanities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Life sciences; Malaria; Medical care; Medical sciences; Natural history; Yaws; Yellow fever
- International, 1917-1971; 100; 22 Cubic Feet; 64 __Boxes __22 cubic feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Material, mostly 1947-1965, relating to projects originated by international organizations or involving more than one country. This includes the Villa Serbelloni conferences and symposia.
  Arrangement note
  The 100 series is divided into 18 subseries as follows: 100 (No program letter, general material which does not fit into a particular program area) 100 A Medical Sciences 100 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing) 100 D Natural Sciences and Agriculture 100 E Fellowships, Scholarships, Training Awards 100 EA Medical Fellowships 100 EC Nursing Fellowships 100 ED Natural Science Fellowships 100 EL Public Health Fellowships 100 ER Humanities Fellowships 100 ES Social Science Fellowships 100 EY Division of Medicine and Public Health Fellowships 100 F Declinations (only declinations of exceptional interest are retained) 100 L Public Health Education (schools of hygiene and public health) 100 O Yellow Fever 100 R Humanities and Arts 100 S Social Sciences 100 V Virus Studies
  - Aannestad, Elling, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AAN-1 Aannestad, Elling "Miscellaneous Memoranda" Volume I, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AAN-1 Aannestad, Elling "Miscellaneous Memoranda" Volume II, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AAN-2 Aannestad, Elling "Value" Inquiry Volume I, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AAN-2 Aannestad, Elling "Value" Inquiry Volume II, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AAN-2 Aannestad, Elling "Value" Inquiry Volume III, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AAN-2 Aannestad, Elling "Value" Inquiry Volume IV, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Agriculture Consultants - (Successor to A. R. Mann), 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Arid Lands Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Atlantic Institute - Education Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Atlantic Institute - Young Leaders Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Atomic Energy - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Biological Theory and Philosophy Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Biological Theory and Philosophy Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bonding of Personnel, 1929, 1934, 1939-1950 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bonding of Personnel, 1951-1961, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Campaigns Against Hunger - (Book - E.C. Stakman, Richard Brafield, Paul C. Mangelsdorf), 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Child Care Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1969-1970, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Child Care Conference - (Villa Serbelloni) - Supplemental Material, 1967-1969; 12 items contained in folders 19-20. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Child Care Conference - (Villa Serbelloni) - Supplemental Material, 1967-1969; 12 items contained in folders 19-20. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - (General), 1926-1949 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - A - B, 1926-1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - C - R, 1926-1971 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - S - Z, 1926-1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Claims (Unsubstantiated) - S - Z, 1926-1971 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Collected Papers - Grant, John B., 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Collected Papers - Grant, John B., 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Collected Papers - Grant, John B. - ("Health Care for the Community" - Draft Copy), 1962 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - College Women in England and America - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Commonwealth Fellows Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom - Hungarian Performing Artists, January - May 1957 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom - Hungarian Performing Artists, June 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom - Hungarian Performing Artists, June 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom - Science and Freedom - Visits, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Division of Medicine and Public Health - Laboratories, 1951-1955 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Division of Medicine and Public Health - Laboratories, 1951-1955 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Division of Medicine and Public Health - Laboratories, 1951-1955 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Division of Medicine and Public Health - Laboratories - Personnel, 1951-1955 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Division of Medicine and Public Health - Laboratories - Personnel - (A-Z), 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Economic Commission for Asia and the Far East - Demography, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Economic Commission for Europe - Conference, 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Economic Commission for Europe - (Ingvar Svennilson), 1948-1955 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Economic Commission for Europe - Scholarships, 1947-1955 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Economic Commission for Europe - Scholarships, 1947-1955 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Economic Commission for Europe - Scholarships, 1947-1955 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Energy Utilization - (Conference, Program Consultants), 1967 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Ecumenical Institute for Advanced Theological Research - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - European Democracies Political Study - (Conferences, Villa Serbelloni), 1962, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Foot and Mouth Disease - (Conference, Program Consultants), 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - International Association of Agricultural Librarians - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - International Association of Penal Law - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - International Association of Universities - Conference - (Travel Grant), 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - International Association of Universities - Economics of Education - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - International Astronomical Union - (Conference, Travel Grants), 1945-1948, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - International Atomic Energy Agency - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1963 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - International Broadcast Institute - Planning Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - International Broadcast Institute - Planning Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - International Bureau of Weights and Measures - (Plaque of Recognition), 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - International Commission on Radiological Protection - Conference, 1958-1961 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - International Commission on Radiological Protection - Conference - Reports, 1954-1959; 4 items (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - International Commission on Radiological Units - Conference, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - International Committee on Chinese Studies - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - International Committee of Agricultural Economics - (Conference, Travel Grants), 1958-1968 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - International Committee of Agricultural Economics - (Conference, Travel Grants), 1958-1968 (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Conference on Scientific Information, 1957-1959, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - International Conference on Scientific Information - (Preprints of Papers), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - International Congress on Medical Librarianship - (Conference, Travel Grant), 1961-1964 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - International Congress on Nutrition - (Conference, Travel Grants), 1957-1964, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - International Congress on Nutrition - Child Health - (Conferences), 1962-1964, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - International Corresponding Club - Conference, 1956-1958 (Box 12, Folder 76)
  - International Economic History Association - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - International Epidemiological Association - Conference, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - International Institute for Educational Planning - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - International Institute of Science and Technology - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - International Planned Parenthood Federation - Conference, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - International Press Institute, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 82)
  - International Press Institute, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - International Press Institute, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - International Press Institute, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - International Press Institute, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - International Press Institute, 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 87)
  - International Press Institute, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 88)
  - International Press Institute, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - International Press Institute, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - International Press Institute, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 91)
  - International Press Institute, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 93)
  - International Press Institute, 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - International Press Institute, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - International Press Institute, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 95)
  - International Press Institute, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 96)
  - International Press Institute, 1962-1968 (Box 15, Folder 97)
  - International Press Institute - Publications - IPI 1-3, 1952, 1954, 1956; 5 items (Box 15, Folder 98)
  - International Press Institute - Publications - IPI 4-12, 1953-1956, 1959, 1961; 8 items contained in folders 99-100. (Box 16, Folder 99)
  - International Press Institute - Publications - IPI 4-12, 1953-1956, 1959, 1961; 8 items contained in folders 99-100. (Box 16, Folder 100)
  - International Press Institute - Reports, 1951-1952; 3 items (Box 16, Folder 101)
  - International Schools Foundation, Inc., 1955-1961 (Box 16, Folder 102)
  - International Schools Foundation, Inc., 1955-1961 (Box 16, Folder 103)
  - International Study of University Admissions - (Conference, Villa Serbelloni), 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 104)
  - International Study of University Admissions - (Report - "Access to Higher Education"), 1963 (Box 17, Folder 105)
  - International Symposium on Space Research - (National Academy of Sciences - National Research Council), 1961 (Box 17, Folder 106)
  - International Union of Biological Schiences - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 107)
  - Learning Conference - (Analogy Symposium, Villa Serbelloni), 1964-1966 (Box 17, Folder 108)
  - Nutrition Conference - (Protein in Cereal Grains), 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 109)
  - Pacific Science Association, 1949-1954 (Box 17, Folder 110)
  - Pacific Science Association, 1949-1954 (Box 17, Folder 111)
  - Pacific Science Association - Report, 1951; 1 item (Box 17, Folder 112)
  - Parliamentary Government Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1961-1963, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 113)
  - Plant Cell Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 114)
  - Plant Cell Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 115)
  - Plant Pathology - (Book - Principles of Plant Pathology, E. C. Stakman, J. G. Harrar), 1957-1958, 1960-1961, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 116)
  - Practical Malariology - (Book - Paul F. Russell, Luther S. West, Reginald D. Manwell), 1957-1958, 1960-1963 (Box 18, Folder 117)
  - Primer for Agricultural Libraries, 1966-1970 (Box 18, Folder 118)
  - Quality of Human Environment - Conference, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 119)
  - Reproductive Biology - Conference, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 120)
  - Rodents - (Conference), 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 121)
  - Rodents - (Conference), 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 122)
  - Scholarships - Directory, 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Social Welfare - Family Service, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 124)
  - Strategy for the Conquest of Hunger - Symposium, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 125)
  - Strategy for the Conquest of Hunger - Symposium - (Facilities), 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 126)
  - Strategy for the Conquest of Hunger - Symposium - (Planning), 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 127)
  - Strategy for the Conquest of Hunger - Symposium - (Publicity), 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 128)
  - Student Unrest Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1967-1971 (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Student Unrest Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1967-1971 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Toxoplasmosis Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1966-1967 (Box 20, Folder 131)
  - UNESCO - Haiti - Education, 1947-1952, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 132)
  - UNESCO - Haiti - Education, 1947-1952, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 133)
  - UNESCO - Haiti - Education, 1947-1952, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 134)
  - UNESCO - Haiti - Education, 1947-1952, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 135)
  - UNESCO - Haiti - Education, 1947-1952, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 136)
  - UNESCO - Haiti - Education - Supplemental Material, 1950; 3 items (Box 20, Folder 137)
  - UNESCO - Peace Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - United Nations - Food and Agriculture Organization - Liason Officers, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 139)
  - United Nations - International Children's Emergency Fund - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1963-1964 (Box 21, Folder 140)
  - United Nations - International Comparison Project - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 141)
  - United Nations - Radiation Statistics - Seminar, 1960-1961 (Box 21, Folder 142)
  - United Nations - Refugee Study, 1951-1954 (Box 21, Folder 143)
  - United Nations - Refugee Study, 1951-1954 (Box 21, Folder 144)
  - United Nations - Refugee Study, 1951-1954 (Box 21, Folder 145)
  - United Nations - Refugee Study, 1951-1954 (Box 21, Folder 146)
  - United Nations - Refugee Study - Preliminary Report, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 147)
  - United Nations - Training and Research Institute, 1964-1966, 1983-1984, 1986, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 148)
  - United Nations - Training and Research Institute - Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1965 (Box 22, Folder 149)
  - United Nations - World Health Organization - Calderwood, Howard B., 1958-1962 (Box 22, Folder 150)
  - United Nations - World Health Organization - Hookworm Diseases Bibliography, 1962-1964 (Box 22, Folder 151)
  - United Nations - World Health Organization - Read, Margaret Helen - (Travel Grant), 1959 (Box 22, Folder 152)
  - United Nations - World Health Organization - Sanitary Engineering Seminar, 1950-1952 (Box 22, Folder 153)
  - Unity of Knowledge Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1967-1968 (Box 22, Folder 154)
  - Universities in Crisis - (Conference, Program Committee), 1969 (Box 22, Folder 155)
  - University Administration - Conference - (South African Investments), 1969 (Box 22, Folder 156)
  - World Population Conference - American Participants - (Travel Grants), 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 157)
  - World Population Conference - Foreign Participants - (Travel Grants), 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 158)
  - World University Service - Hungarian Students, 1956-1958 (Box 22, Folder 159)
  - World University Service - Hungarian Students, 1956-1958 (Box 22, Folder 160)
  - International - Medical Sciences, 100.A
    - Community Medicine Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), 1967-July 1968 (Box 22, Folder 161)
    - Community Medicine Conference - (Villa Serbelloni), August 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 162)
    - Community Medicine Conference - Proceedings - Volume I - IV, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 163)
    - Community Medicine Conference - Proceedings - Volume I - IV, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 164)
    - Community Medicine Conference - Proceedings - Volume I - IV, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 165)
    - Community Medicine Conference - Proceedings - Volume I - IV, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 166)
    - Community Medicine Conference - Proceedings - Volume V, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 167)
    - International Council on Contraceptive Development, 1969-1971 (Box 24, Folder 168)
    - International Physiological Congress - (Travel Grants), 1946-1950, 1952-1953 (Box 24, Folder 169)
    - International Rescue Committee - Polish Medical Aid - (Pharmaceutical Supplies), 1958-1960 (Box 24, Folder 170)
    - International Union for the Scientific Study of Population - Conference, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 171)
  - International - Nursing, 100.C
    - Florence Nightingale International Foundation - Conference - (Nursing), 1954-1957, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 172)
    - International Council of Nurses - Broe, Ellen Johanne - (Travel Grant), 1959 (Box 24, Folder 173)
    - International Council of Nurses - Sher, Alice C. P. - (Travel Grant), 1960 (Box 24, Folder 174)
  - International - Natural Sciences and Agriculture, 100.D
    - Cattle Diseases Conference - (Villa Serbelloni) - (East Coast Fever and Trypanosomiasis), 1968-September 1969 (Box 24, Folder 175)
    - Cattle Diseases Conference - (Villa Serbelloni) - (East Coast Fever and Trypanosomiasis), October 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 176)
    - Cattle Diseases Conference - (Villa Serbelloni) - (East Coast Fever and Trypanosomiasis), October 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 177)
    - Cereal Crops Germplasm - Conference - (Program Consultant), 1969 (Box 25, Folder 178)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom - Science and Freedom - (Conference), 1953-1957 (Box 25, Folder 179)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom - Science and Freedom - (Conference), 1953-1957 (Box 25, Folder 180)
    - Council for International Organizations of Medical Science - (Abnormal Hemoglobins Seminar, Travel Grants), 1955-1959 (Box 25, Folder 181)
    - Crop Improvement Conference, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 182)
    - Desalinzed Water - Conference, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 183)
    - Insect and Mite Control - Conference, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 184)
    - International Association for Plant Taxonomy - (Travel Grants), 1955-1956 (Box 26, Folder 185)